(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T13:54:22.921429",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
はるか昔、西の海に沈んだとされる伝説の都市、アトロポリス。
Long ago, the legendary city of Atropolis was said to have sunk into the western sea.
そんな誰もいないはずの海の底に、ロボットの少女がひとり。
At the bottom of that sea, where no one should be, stood a single robot girl.
彼女の歌声は、都市を再び浮上させる唯一の鍵。
Her singing voice is the only key that can make the city rise again.
「今宵…この街を再び地上へ…」
"Tonight... bring this city back to the surface..."
ダメ ダメ ダメ 脳味噌の中殻からやめろ
No, no, no, stop it from inside your brain,
バカと阿呆と巡り会うモラリティ
morality meeting fools and idiots.
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン
Darling, baby, darling,
半端なくラブ ときめき 浮き足立たすフィロソフィ
half-hearted love, fluttering philosophy.
シノホドカワイウメズガ 何が四方に触れるくらい
So cute it hurts, touching everything around.
ばらまくラッシング 気付けば当然 このように生まれて君が悪い
Scattering a rush, naturally born to be creepy.
やたらと死にたい 恋煩い ぱらぱらみだら 頭とこの身体
Reckless lovesickness, scattered obscenity in head and body.
けど脈から愛欲が切れて アイリスアウト
But desire cuts off from my pulse, iris out.
一体どうしよう このままだいどうしよう
What on earth should I do, what should I do now?
暴れのゴザラメが 溶けてゲロになりそう
The raging sugar looks like it's melting into vomit.
どこかバチ開いて 溺れ死にそう
Opening somewhere, looking like I'll drown.
今この世で君だけが大正解
Right now in this world, only you are the right answer.
シノホドカワイウメズガ 何が四方に触れるくらい
So cute it hurts, touching everything around.
ばらまくラッシング 気付けば当然 このように生まれて君が悪い
Scattering a rush, naturally born to be creepy.
立ち回ってもいい なんでもいい 今君と舐めているすべて惜しい
I'll take any stance, anything is fine, tasting everything with you is regrettable.
けど脈から愛欲が切れて アイリスアウト
But desire cuts off from my pulse, iris out.
一体どうしよう このままだいどうしよう
What on earth should I do, what should I do now?
暴れのゴザラメが 溶けてゲロになりそう
The raging sugar looks like it's melting into vomit.
どこかバチ開いて 溺れ死にそう
Opening somewhere, looking like I'll drown.
今この世で君だけが大正解
Right now in this world, only you are the right answer.
好き 嫌い 好き 嫌い
Like, dislike, like, dislike...
自己満 途中半端 はやめて
Stop with the self-satisfied, half-assed attitude.
一番ダサいことの体現者
The embodiment of the lamest thing ever.
一生飼い犬にでもなるつもり
Planning to be a pet dog for life.
満身創痍で血を覚醒 もういいかい まだだよ
Wounded all over, awakening my blood. Ready yet? Not yet!
もういいかい 大好きを貫け
Ready yet? Stick to loving it!
未公開 もういいかい
Undisclosed, ready yet?
もうもういいよね 強制 Let's go!
That's enough, right? Forced, let's go!
僕は僕が嫌い 愛せない
I hate myself, I can't love myself.
声も顔も嫌い 大嫌い
I hate my voice, my face, I hate it all.
今日も作り笑い 愛せない
Smiling fakely today too, can't love it.
過去は死んだ 未来大嫌い
The past is dead, I hate the future.
誰のせいだ 僕のせいじゃない
Whose fault is it? It's not my fault.
自慰行為 何も生まれない同輩
Masturbatory acts, companions producing nothing.
消耗 尻尾取り合う猿芝居
Exhaustion, monkey business chasing tails.
自暴自棄 位がちょうどいい 自分を投げ捨てて自分覚醒
Self-abandonment is just right, throw myself away and awaken.
もういいかい まあだだよ
Ready yet? Not yet!
もういいかい 大好きを貫け
Ready yet? Stick to loving it!
未公開 もういいかい
Undisclosed, ready yet?
もうもういいよね 蘇生 Let's go!
That's enough, right? Revival, let's go!
僕は君が嫌い 愛せない
I hate you, I can't love you.
パパもママも嫌い 大嫌い
I hate mom and dad too, I hate them all.
皆被害者みたい 愛せない
Everyone acts like a victim, can't love it.
僕ら生きる機械大嫌い
We are living machines, I hate it.
誰のせいだ 僕は悪くない
Whose fault is it? I didn't do anything wrong.
大好き 大好き 大好き
Love, love, love...
己満 中途半端はやめて
Stop the self-satisfied, half-hearted stuff,
一番ダサいことの体現者
the embodiment of the lamest things ever.
一生飼い犬にでもなるつもり
Planning to be a pet dog for life,
満身創痍で血を覚醒
awakening my blood covered in wounds.
もういいかい
Are you ready?
まだだよ
Not yet.
もういいかい
Are you ready?
大好きを貫け
Pierce the love.
未公開 もういいかい
Undisclosed, are you ready?
もういいよね 強制 let's go!
OK, ready! Obligation, let's go!
好き 嫌い 大嫌い 好き
Like, dislike, hate, like,
like, dislike, hate, like.
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 大好き
Dislike, dislike, dislike, love.
僕は僕が嫌い 愛せない
I dislike myself, unable to love.
声も顔も嫌い 大嫌い
I dislike my voice and face, I hate them.
今日も作り笑い 愛せない
Forced smiles again today, unable to love.
過去は死んだ 未来大嫌い
The past is dead, I hate the future.
誰のせいだ 僕のせいじゃない
Whose fault is it? It's not my fault.
自慰行為 何も生まない 同士
Masturbation, companion that won't deliver,
消耗 搾り合う 猿芝居
exhaustion, a shit show of an affair.
自暴自棄 位がちょうどいい
Self-abandonment seems just right,
己を投げ捨てて 自己覚醒
throwing away myself and the self awakens.
もういいかい まだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet.
もういいかい 大好きを貫け
Are you ready? Pierce the love.
未公開 もういいかい もういいよね
Undisclosed, are you ready? OK, ready!
蘇生 let's go!
Revival, let's go!
好き 嫌い 大嫌い 好き
Like, dislike, hate, like,
like, dislike, hate, like.
僕は君が嫌い 愛せない
I dislike you, unable to love.
パパもママも嫌い 大嫌い
I dislike mom and dad too, I hate them.
皆被害者みたい 愛せない
Everyone plays the victim, unable to love.
僕ら生きる機械 大嫌い
We are living machines, I hate it.
誰のせいだ 僕は悪くない
Whose fault is it? I didn't do anything wrong.
好き 嫌い 大嫌い 好き
Like, dislike, hate, like...
手鏡なんて見ないで
Don't look in your hand mirror,
起死回生 先をにらみ再生
resuscitation, glare ahead, restoration.
自信は後からついて来る
Confidence comes afterwards,
いっぽ踏み出したなら cool
if you step forward, that's cool.
最初の動機をもう一度思い出そう
Remember your initial motives again,
悔しい今日をひっくり返そう
let's turn around today's frustration.
安心してるうちは 誰にもなれない
While feeling relieved, you can't become anyone.
君になれるのは君だけ
The only one you can become is you.
あなたはすぐに写真を撮りたがる
You always want to take pictures right away,
あたしは何時も其れを嫌がるの だって写真になっちゃえばあたしが古くなるじゃない
and I always hate that... because if we become a photograph, won't I grow old?
あなたはすぐに絶対などと言う
You always use words like "absolute,"
あたしは何時も其れを嫌がるの
and I always hate that.
だって冷めてしまえば其れすら嘘になるじゃない
Because if our feelings cool down, even that will turn into a lie.
don't u θink? i 絛 b wiθ u
Don't you think? I wanna be with you.
此処に居て
Stay right here,
ずっと ずっと ずっと
always, always, always.
明日のことは判らない
I don't know what tomorrow will bring,
だからぎゅっとしていてね
so hold me tight.
ぎゅっとしていてね ダーリン
Hold me tight, darling.
あなたはすぐにおじけて見せ付ける
You always try to act all sulky,
あたしは何時も其れを喜ぶの
and I'm always happy about that
だってカートみたいだからあたしがコートニーじゃない
because you're like Kurt and I'm not Courtney.
don't u θink? i 絛 b wiθ u
Don't you think? I wanna be with you.
傍に来て
Come closer,
もっと もっと もっと
more and more and more.
昨日のことは忘れちゃおう
Let's forget about yesterday's events,
そしてぎゅっとしていてね ぎゅっとしていてね ダーリン
and hold me tight, darling.
また四月が来たよ同じ日のことを思い出して
April has come once again, remembering the same day.
don't u θink? i 絛 b wiθ u
Don't you think? I wanna be with you.
此処に居て
Stay right here,
ずっと ずっと ずっと
always, always, always.
明日のことは判らない
I don't know what tomorrow will bring,
だからぎゅっとしていてね
so hold me tight.
i 絛 b wiθ u 傍に来て
I wanna be with you, come closer,
もっと もっと もっと
more and more and more.
昨日のことは忘れちゃおう
Let's forget about yesterday's events,
そしてぎゅっとしていてね ぎゅっとしていてね ダーリン
and hold me tight, darling.
あなたはすぐに意じけで見せ付ける
You always try to act all sulky,
あたしは何時も其れを喜ぶの
and I'm always happy about that
だってカートみたいだからあたしがコートニーじゃない
because you're like Kurt and I'm not Courtney.
don't u θink? i 絛 b wiθ u
Don't you think? I wanna be with you.
傍に来て
Come closer,
もっと もっと もっと
more and more and more.
昨日のことは忘れちゃおう
Let's forget about yesterday's events,
そしてぎゅっとしていてね
and hold me tight.
また四月が来たよ同じ日のことを思い出して
April has come once again, remembering the same day.
don't u θink? i 絛 b wiθ u
Don't you think? I wanna be with you.
此処に居て
Stay right here,
ずっと ずっと ずっと
always, always, always.
明日のことは判らない
I don't know what tomorrow will bring,
だからぎゅっとしていてね
so hold me tight.
i 絛 b wiθ u 傍に来て
I wanna be with you, come closer,
もっと もっと もっと
more and more and more.
昨日のことは忘れちゃおう
Let's forget about yesterday's events,
そしてぎゅっとしていてね ぎゅっとしていてね ダーリン
and hold me tight, darling.
ぎゅっとしていてね ぎゅっとしていてね ダーリン
Hold me tight, darling.
ぎゅっとしていてね ぎゅっとしていてね
Hold me tight, hold me tight.
ぎゅっとしていてね 傍に来て
Hold me tight... come closer...
ずっと
Forever...
明日のことは分からない
We don't know about tomorrow,
だからぎゅっとしていてね
so please hold me tight.
ぎゅっとしていてね ダーリン
Please hold me tight, darling.
i wanna be with you
傍に来て もっと もっと もっと
come closer, more and more and more.
もっと もっと もっと もっと
More and more and more and more.
昨日のことは
Let's forget
忘れちゃおう
about yesterday,
そしてぎゅっとしていてね
and please hold me tight.
ぎゅっとしていてね ダーリン
Please hold me tight, darling.
ダーリン
Darling.
はーい！というわけで、ロボ子！
Ha-ii! And with that, Roboco!
ホロライブ0期生、最高出力のロボットのロボ子だよー！
Hololive 0th Gen's max-power robot, Roboco-dayo!
今日は私の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live today!
というわけで、さっそく愛してる
So, we right away performed 'Aishiteiru',
大好き with テレローダー、そして
'Daisuki with Teleloader', and
ゲームスの3曲をね、歌わせていただきました！
then 'Gips'—those three songs!
いかがでしたでしょうか？
How was it?
そしていかがでしょうか、このステージ！
And how about this stage?
まだね、この衣装のモチーフではないんですけど
It's not quite based on this costume, but
新衣装のパラシュート衣装にちなんで作ってみました！
we made it in theme with my new 'Parachute' outfit!
このステージはもうさっきの3曲でも分かるんだけど
As you can tell from those first three songs,
これからどんどん化けるので、楽しみにしていてください。
it's going to transform more and more, so please look forward to it.
いろんなね、姿で楽しめる。今はめっちゃ、
You can enjoy it in various forms. Right now it's super...
ほにゃ、ほにゃ、ほにゃ、ほにゃ、魚も骨！
...hnya, hnya, hnya, hnya, even the fish are bones!
え、めちゃめちゃ可愛くない？
Eh, isn't it super cute?
大好きなんだよね。
I just love it.
そう、こちらはですね、海底が、海底都市がテーマになっていまして
Yes, this is themed around an undersea city,
こちらの都市の名前は、え、冒頭のオープニングでも言っていたんですが、「@Robopolis」、「@Robopolis」と言います。
and the name of this city, as I mentioned in the opening, is '@Robopolis'.
ロボじゃない、ロボ！ロボ、ロボでロボ！
Not Robo, Robo! Robo, Robo with Robo!
本来は海の底にある都市なんですけれども、
Originally it's a city at the bottom of the sea, but
1日だけロボ子の歌のパワーで浮上させているんだよ。
for just one day, we're floating it up with the power of Roboco's singing.
どうだ、すごいだろ！
How's that, amazing right?
そこは息吸えるの？
Can you breathe there?
是非ね、いっぱいたくさんスクリーンショットを、
Please take lots and lots of screenshots—
もう撮ってると思うけど、いっぱい撮ってこちらのハッシュタグもね、「#ロボ子海底3Dライブ」でドシドシポストしてくれたら嬉しいです！
I'm sure you already are, but I'd be so happy if you post them with the hashtag '#RobocoSeabed3DLive'!
トレンドに入りたい！よろしくお願いします！
I want to trend! Please support me!
誕生日が終わってしまったけど、誕生日のライブのつもりでやっていますので、
Even though my birthday has passed, we're doing this as my birthday live, so...
ね、ね、いつもね、いつもやらせていただいてますので、
you know, we always do this, so...
ぜひよろしくお願いします。
please look forward to it.
今回のタグは「ロボ子海底3Dライブ」でございます。よろしくね！
Today's hashtag is '#RobocoSeabed3DLive'. Please use it!
はい。というわけでね、どうでしたか、ちなみに。
Right. So, how was it, by the way?
かっこよかった？
Was it cool?
去年は龍とかに乗ってみたんだけど、今回はアトロポリスなんで鮫とかにも乗ってみました。
Last year I rode a dragon, but this time since it's Atropolis, I rode a shark too.
はい、今年もメロ女は目指してみたいって、あのメロ女になっていました？
Yeah, this year I wanted to aim for 'melo-onna'—did I become a melo-onna?
メロ女。今年はメロ女目指したいと思います。はい。
Melo-onna. I want to aim to be a melo-onna this year. Yes.
まだね、あ、そう、気づいた？フリフリしてきたやつ。
Also, oh right, did you notice? The frilly thing swaying.
実は今回は今年は時間に余裕があったので、事前に
Actually, this time we had some extra time, so in advance
ロボサァ達にね、募集をさせてくれて、イラストが上から降ってくるようなギミックをね、用意いたしました。
we asked fans to submit illustrations, and prepared a gimmick where illustrations rain down from above.
採用された方はね、え、もしかして自分のがあんのかも知れないって言うドキドキを
Those who were selected might have felt that nervous excitement of 'Could that be mine?'
味わいながら探してみててください。まだまだ出てきますのでね。
Try savoring it as you look. There's still more to come!
チャンスはまだまだあります。
There are still plenty of chances.
誰が、誰が書いたのが選ばれているのか、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
Please look forward to whose drawings were chosen.
めちゃめちゃもう可愛いやつがいっぱい出てきてますのでね。
There are so many super cute ones coming out.
うーん。
Hmm.
ゆっくり見てってくださーい。
Please take your time and watch.
はい。それでは、まだまだありますので、
Alright. Well then, there's still more, so
ここからはなんと、ゲストも登場するので、
from here on, guest stars will also appear!
うわ、いったい何やったんだ！
Whoa, what on earth did they do?!
楽しみにしていてください。
Please look forward to it.
それじゃあ、まだまだいくぞー！
Well then, we're still going!
見てって、ポーズしてってー！
Watch and strike a pose!
ポシャ！
Poshya!
小さな その両手に抱えきれない夢
Small dreams that cannot be held in both hands,
こうして今大人になって思い出してる
growing up into an adult now and remembering.
小さな出来事に悩んででもがいている僕を見て
Watching myself worry and struggle over trivial things,
あの日の僕はなんて言うのかな
what would the me of that day say?
街中を包む風にふわり乗って（始まるストーリー）さあ旅に出よう
Riding softly on the wind wrapping the town... Now let's set out on a journey.
スターリングスター 瞬く間に広がる奇跡みたいな夜
Starring star, a miraculous night spreading in a blink,
この胸に覚えている大切なぬくもりも
and the precious warmth I remember in this chest too.
スターリングスター まぶゆく降りそそぐ スター かき集めたら
Starring star, if I gather up the dazzlingly falling stars,
きっと今よりちょっと強くなれるって思ったんだ
I thought I could surely become a bit stronger than now.
汗にまみれてた昔ほど光り輝いて見えるけど
It looks even more dazzling than the past covered in sweat,
今の僕に嘘はないから
but there are no lies in me right now.
小高い丘に駆け上がって街を見下ろして
Running up a small hill and looking down at the town,
（溢れるメロディ）明日を探して歌うよ
singing as I search for tomorrow.
スターリングスター 瞬く間に広がる奇跡みたいな夜
Starring star, a miraculous night spreading in a blink,
この胸に覚えている大切なぬくもりも
and the precious warmth I remember in this chest too.
スターリングスター まぶゆく降りそそぐ スター 巡り会えたら
Starring star, if we happen to meet the dazzlingly falling stars,
きっと今よりちょっと強くなれるって
I thought I could surely become a bit stronger than now.
小さな その両手に抱えきれない夢
Small dreams that cannot be held in both hands,
こうして今大人になって思い出してる
growing up into an adult now and remembering.
小さな出来事に悩んででもがいている僕を見て
Watching myself worry and struggle over trivial things,
あの日の僕はなんて言うのかな
what would the me of that day say?
街中を包む風にふわり乗って（始まるストーリー）さあ旅に出よう
Riding softly on the wind wrapping the town... Now let's set out on a journey.
スターリングスター 瞬く間に広がる奇跡みたいな夜
Starring star, a miraculous night spreading in a blink,
この胸に覚えている大切なぬくもりも
and the precious warmth I remember in this chest too.
スターリングスター まぶゆく降りそそぐ スター かき集めたら
Starring star, if I gather up the dazzlingly falling stars,
きっと今よりちょっと強くなれるって思ったんだ
I thought I could surely become a bit stronger than now.
夜更かししたい見下ろしたいでも概要はさっさとだまらっしゃい
Want to stay up late, want to look down, but summary, hurry up and shut up.
騒ぎ立てるよりこの瞬間大事にしたい
Want to cherish this moment rather than making a fuss.
泥沼のような焦燥感色んな動揺で揺るるのは
Feeling impatient like a swamp, swaying with various turbulences
過去じゃなく未来だけ
is only about the future, not the past.
息をのむくらいのスピードで七色のスターマイン
Rainbow starmine at a breathtaking speed,
釘付けになるの針さけ
piercing the needle as I'm glued to it.
スターマインさあ打ち上げろ
Starmine, come on, launch it up!
小さな その両手に抱えきれない夢
Small dreams that cannot be held in both hands,
こうして今大人になって思い出してる
growing up into an adult now and remembering.
小さな出来事に悩んででもがいている僕を見て
Watching myself worry and struggle over trivial things,
あの日の僕はなんて言うのかな
what would the me of that day say?
街中を包む風にふわり乗って（始まるストーリー）さあ旅に出よう
Riding softly on the wind wrapping the town... Now let's set out on a journey.
スターリングスター 瞬く間に広がる奇跡みたいな夜
Starring star, a miraculous night spreading in a blink,
この胸に覚えている大切なぬくもりも
and the precious warmth I remember in this chest too.
スターリングスター まぶゆく降りそそぐ スター かき集めたら
Starring star, if I gather up the dazzlingly falling stars,
きっと今よりちょっと強くなれるって思ったんだ
I thought I could surely become a bit stronger than now.
真っ暗な空を照らす 命の火花散らそう
Lighting up the pitch-black sky, let's scatter sparks of life.
悲しみも吹き飛ばせ 最大火力で
Blow away sadness too with maximum firepower.
さあ打ち上げろ
Come on, launch it up!
小さな その両手に抱えきれない夢
Small dreams that cannot be held in both hands,
こうして今大人になって思い出してる
growing up into an adult now and remembering.
小さな出来事に悩んででもがいている僕を見て
Watching myself worry and struggle over trivial things,
あの日の僕はなんて言うのかな
what would the me of that day say?
街中を包む風にふわり乗って（始まるストーリー）さあ旅に出よう
Riding softly on the wind wrapping the town... Now let's set out on a journey.
スターリングスター 瞬く間に広がる奇跡みたいな夜
Starring star, a miraculous night spreading in a blink,
この胸に覚えている大切なぬくもりも
and the precious warmth I remember in this chest too.
スターリングスター まぶゆく降りそそぐ スター かき集めたら
Starring star, if I gather up the dazzlingly falling stars,
人生は七転びやおっきゅう点がい
life has seven falls and big awakenings.
タッタラタラッタ タッタッタッタ タッタラタラッタ タッタッタッタ
Tattara taratta tattattatta...
君と過ごす夜少しアーバン 処理速度高速私から送るデータは膨大
Spending the night with you, a bit urban. High-speed processing, massive data sent from me.
「無理、受け取れない」とかダメだよ！愛して twinkle night
"No, I can't accept it" is no good! Love me, twinkle night.
君と過ごす夜少しアーバン 甘々なしとひととき君にオーダー
Spending the night with you, a bit urban. Ordering sweet moments from you.
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban
処理速度高速 私から
Processing speed high, from me
送るデータは膨大 無理、受け取れない
The data sent is massive; no way, I can't receive it
とかダメだよ！ 愛して twinkle night
Don't say that! Love me, twinkle night
昨日の暮らしは悪くなる一方です
Yesterday's living is only getting worse
君と二人暮らす部屋が理想です
A room where the two of us live together is ideal
咽頭が上がらない僕のそばでずっと
Right by my side where my voice won't rise
笑ってくれる君が好きです
I love the you who smiles for me
最高だよ人生 長い髪切って
Life is the best, cutting my long hair
君の好きな誰かに合わせて
Matching someone you like
音楽をかけるよ 僕がDJのradio
Playing music, I'm the radio DJ
ポルノグラフィティみたいな感じと
Like a Pornograffiti kind of feel
目と目が合うレーザービーム
Eyes meeting in a laser beam
漫画的偶然 手が触れた日
A manga-like coincidence, the day our hands touched
放電する二人 電気がお互いバチバチ
Discharging couple, electricity crackling between us
特性：蓄電、避雷針
Trait: electricity storage, lightning rod
唐突にしゃべりだすSiri
Siri suddenly starts talking
君の言葉の裏 本当の意味
The real meaning behind your words
これっきりぎりぎりで保ってるボクのハート
My heart barely holding on for the last time
プラ製でもう溶けそう
Made of plastic, about to melt already
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban
ティンクル来る世だ マザータックザスラでスラ
Twinkle coming world, Mars Attacks, Zathura
全部架空ヒエログラフだって
All fictional hieroglyphs
誰かの解釈読めるわけない
No way to read anyone's interpretation
ないのだけれど
Even if there isn't
この物語はフィクションです
This story is fiction
君との遭遇は嘘なんです
Encountering you is a lie
feel alright 痛くも痒くもない
Feel alright, neither painful nor itchy
けど黄色ゲージ、スタミナない
But yellow gauge, no stamina
教えてfilmarks 空っぽの人生 星何点？
Tell me, Filmarks, how many stars for an empty life?
欲しがっている満点の星
The perfect stars I desire
120個 いや一個で十分かも
120, no, one might be enough
wow signal送り返す 君は返事もくれないまま
Sending back a wow signal, you still don't reply
炭酸のないサイダー 飲み干せない まだまだ
Cider without carbonation, can't finish drinking it yet
裸足のまま踊る夜 寒くはないけどココアを飲む
Dancing barefoot at night, not cold, but drinking cocoa
誰かが見てる 私も誰かを見てる
Someone is watching, I'm watching someone too
いちまるはち アメと恋とゲーム
108, candy and love and games
最高のfriendだ お布団
The best friend is a futon
（ぎゅうぎゅう） twinkle night たゆたう
Twinkle night, drifting
夢遊病患者の寝言
Somnambulist's sleep-talking
甘い雲はバニラの香りがするんだ
Sweet clouds smell like vanilla
包んだはずの足は寒くて引っ込めたい
Feet that should have been wrapped are cold, I want to pull them in
きっとまた、はみ出したまま寝てしまったんだ
Surely I fell asleep with them sticking out again
またあったまったら、あなた
Once warmed up again, you
あなたとなら ここ5日、10日、100日
With you, 5 days, 10 days, 100 days here
どうか音は星を超えた
Somehow the sound crossed the stars
そうか、やっぱり夢か
I see, it was a dream after all
わかっても瞳は閉じたまま
Even knowing, eyes remain closed
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban
処理速度高速 私から
Processing speed high, from me
送るデータは膨大 無理、受け取れない
The data sent is massive; no way, I can't receive it
とかダメだよ！ 愛して twinkle night
Don't say that! Love me, twinkle night
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban
甘々なひととき 君にオーダー
A sweet moment, ordered for you
コマ送りメモリー
Frame-by-frame memory
イルミの前 手を取り
Taking hands in front of the illumination
言葉と指を交わそうよ
Let's exchange words and fingers
恋のセオリー
The theory of love
昨日の暮らしは悪くなる一方です
Yesterday's living is only getting worse
君と二人暮らす部屋が理想です
A room where the two of us live together is ideal
咽頭が上がらない僕のそばでずっと
Right by my side where my voice won't rise
笑ってくれる君が好きです
I love the you who smiles for me
最高だよ人生 長い髪切って
Life is the best, cutting my long hair
君の好きな誰かに合わせて
Matching someone you like
音楽をかけるよ 僕がDJのradio
Playing music, I'm the radio DJ
ポルノグラフィティみたいな感じと
Like a Pornograffiti kind of feel
目と目が合うレーザービーム
Eyes meeting in a laser beam
漫画的偶然 手が触れた日
A manga-like coincidence, the day our hands touched
放電する二人 電気がお互いバチバチ
Discharging couple, electricity crackling between us
特性：蓄電、避雷針
Trait: electricity storage, lightning rod
唐突にしゃべりだすSiri
Siri suddenly starts talking
君の言葉の裏 本当の意味
The real meaning behind your words
これっきりぎりぎりで保ってるボクのハート
My heart barely holding on for the last time
プラ製でもう溶けそう
Made of plastic, about to melt already
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban
処理速度高速 私から
Processing speed high, from me
送るデータは膨大 無理、受け取れない
The data sent is massive; no way, I can't receive it
とかダメだよ！ 愛して twinkle night
Don't say that! Love me, twinkle night
君と過ごす夜 少しアーバン
Spending the night with you, a bit urban
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
そういう扱い心得てよね
Make sure you know how to treat me like that
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気づくこと
Rule one: Notice when my hairstyle is different from usual
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること いいね?
Rule two: Look all the way down to my shoes, okay?
その三 わたしの一言には三つの言葉で返すること
Rule three: Reply to my single word with three words
わかったら右手がお留守なnosisなんとかして!
If you get that, do something about my right hand being unattended!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm saying anything selfish
キミに心から思って欲しいの かわいいって
I want you to think from your heart that I'm cute
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
気づいて ねえねえ
Notice, hey hey
待たせるなんて論外よ
Making me wait is out of the question
わたしを誰だと思ってるの?
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだか あまいものが食べたい!
I want something sweet all of a sudden!
いますぐにょ?
Right now, okay?
欠点? かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaw? You mean cute, right?
文句は許しませんの
Complaints are not permitted
あのね、私の話ちゃんと聞いてる? ちょっとおう……
Hey, are you listening to my talk properly? Wait...
あ、それとね 白いおううまさん
Oh, and also, a white horsey
決まってるでしょ? 迎えに来て
You know it, come pick me up
わかったら かしずいて 手を取って「おひめさま」って
If you get that, kneel down, take my hand and say "my princess"
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm saying anything selfish
でもね 少しとがっかりしてくれたっていいのよ
But you know, it's alright if you're a little disappointed
世界で私だけのおうじさま
My only prince in the world
気づいて ほらほら
Realize it, hey hey
世界で一番おひめさま
World's number one princess,
そういう扱い心得てよね
make sure you treat me accordingly!
その一 いつもと違う
Number one: Notice when my hairstyle
髪型に気付くこと
is different from usual.
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること いいね?
Number two: Look down at my shoes, okay?
その三 わたしのひとことには三つの言葉で返事すること
Number three: Reply to my every word with three words.
わかったら右手がお留守なのをなんとかして！
When you get that, do something about my lonely right hand!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
キミに心から思って欲しいの かわいいって
I just want you to truly think from your heart... that I'm cute.
世界で一番おひめさま
World's number one princess,
気付いてよ ねえねえ
realize that, hey, hey!
待たせるなんて論外よ
Keeping me waiting is out of the question;
わたしを誰だと思ってるの?
who do you think I am?
もうなんだか甘いものが食べたい！
I feel like having something sweet right now!
いますぐによ
Right this instant!
欠点?かわいいの間違いでしょ文句は許しませんの
Flaws? You must mean cute, and I won't hear any complaints.
あのね、私の話ちゃんと聞いてる?
Hey, are you actually listening to me?
ちょっとお…
Just a sec...
あ、それとね 白いおうまさん 決まってるでしょ 迎えに来て
Oh, and also, a white horse—you know it, come pick me up!
わかったら かしずいて手をとって「おひめさま」って
If you get that, kneel down, take my hand, and say "My princess."
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish...
でもね 少しぐらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ?
though it'd be nice if you scolded me a little bit, you know?
世界でわたしだけのおうじさま
World's only prince for me,
気付いてよ ほらほら
realize that, hey, hey!
お手てが空いてます
Our hands are empty—
無口でぶあいそうなおうじさま
a silent and aloof prince.
もうどうして気付いてよ早く
Why don't you realize it already?
絶対キミはわかってない……わかってないわ……
You surely don't understand... you really don't...
いちごののったshortcake
Shortcake with a strawberry on top,
こだわりたまごのとろけるpudding
meltingly smooth pudding from fine eggs.
みんなみんな我慢します
I'll hold myself back on all of it—
わがままなことと思わないで
don't think I'm just being selfish!
私だってやればできるもん あとで後悔するわよ
I can do it if I try, you'll regret it later!
当然です!だって私は
Naturally! Because I am...
世界で一番おひめさま
the world's number one princess!
ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ?
Make sure you're watching me, or I might go somewhere else!
ふいにだきしめられた 急にそんな え?
Suddenly being hugged... so abruptly, huh?
「ひかれるあぶないよ」そう言ってそっぽむくキミ
"You'll get hit, it's dangerous," you say, looking away.
……こっちの方が危ないわよっ
...This is way more dangerous!
当然ですだって私は
Naturally, because I am
世界で一番大きな王様ちゃんとうみててよね
the world's biggest king—make sure you're watching!
どこかに行っちゃうよ?
Or I might go somewhere else!
ふいにだきしめられた 急にそんな え?
Suddenly being embraced... so suddenly, huh?
「ひかれるあぶないよ」そう言ってそっぽむくきみ
"You'll get hit, it's dangerous," you say, looking away.
……こっちの方が危ないわよっ
...This is way more dangerous!
はーいということで、3曲連続でお届けしましたがどうでしたかー?
Hiii! So, we just delivered three songs in a row—how was it?
ストロベリーに、え、ポルカ、ベちゃ、ビブ、そしてチハ、5人で歌いました！めっちゃめちゃかっこよくなかった?
Strawberry, um, Polka, Beya, Bibu, and Chiha—the five of us sang it! Wasn't it super, super cool?
え、なんかいいよね。なんかみんなで一緒に踊るのっていいよね。
Um, it's nice, right? Dancing together with everyone is really nice.
そしてトゥインクルナイト、え、お、ペコラと一緒に歌いましたー！
And Twinkle Night, um, oh, I sang it together with Pekora-!
そして最後はワールドイズマインCPKのりミックスバージョンになります。世界で一番お姫様だった?お姫様だったー！
And lastly is the World is Mine CPK remix version! Was I the world's number one princess? I was the princess!
ここでもね、みんなに募集したイラストが降ってきたけど、自分の見つけられた人いたかな?見つけたらいっぱい写真撮っといてくださいねー！
Here too, illustrations we requested from everyone came falling down—did anyone find theirs? If you find yours, take lots of pictures, okay?
はい、というわけで3曲をお届けしたんですけど、かっこいいまわり、かわいいまわり、いかがでしたか?
Yes, so we delivered those three songs—how did you like the cool side and the cute side?
え、そう、ステージ流れ星、ぱーって降ってきたの、ほらみて!星空！
Oh, right, shooting stars on stage, they came pouring down—look at that! A starry sky!
すごい、このステージね、マジ無限の可能性を感じるんだよね。なんでもできる気がする。うん。
Amazing, this stage really makes you feel infinite possibilities. It feels like anything is possible. Yeah.
いや、ほらまと一緒に歌えるの楽しいな！いっぱいなんか、1년에1回のこのライブ、思いっきり好きなことできるのがすごい楽しい。そして衣装も久しぶりに和装でございます。
Man, singing together with Holomen is so fun! Doing whatever I love to my heart's content in this once-a-year live is super fun. And for costumes, it's been a while in Japanese attire!
あ、わーるどいずまいんはね、ちょっと、神谷のやつで、いいなって思って歌いたくなっちゃったので、せっかくだから神谷に合わせて和装でね歌ってみました。
Ah, World is Mine, you know, I thought it was nice with Kaguya's version and wanted to sing it, so since we had the chance, I tried singing it in Japanese attire to match Kaguya!
ケーテン?かわいいの間違いでしょ。ポンダっていいでしょ?
"Flaws?" You must mean cute. Ponda is fine, right?
まあ今日ポンはしないんですけどねー。なんかしないけど歌だけは高性能って言われるしな。はい。
Well, I won't do any pon today though. People say my singing alone is high-performance. Haha.
あ、でも、今そんな、そら!って言ってだけど
Ah, but, just now I was saying "Sora!"...
今日限りの また海に沈んじゃうんだってこの場所
This place is only for today, and it's going to sink back into the sea...
そんなのもったいないよね
That would be such a waste, wouldn't it?
ロボ子さん何か いい方法知らない？
Roboco-san, do you know any good ways?
僕が高性能だからきっと知ってるかなって思って
Since I'm high-spec, I thought you'd surely know.
ひらめいた！
I've got it!
海は海でも 電子の海に沈めいちゃえばいいんだ！
Even if it's the sea, we can just sink it into the electronic sea!
いいんだ！そうだよな！
That's right! That's it!
そうだよね！
That's right, isn't it?
というわけで ちょっと やっちゃおうかな？
And with that, shall we give it a try?
お願いします！
Please do!
パチン、これパチンってなった。
*Click*, there it went *click*.
悲しみの海に沈んだ私
Sunk into a sea of grief,
目を開けるのも億劫
it's a bother to even open my eyes.
このままどこまでも堕ちて行き
And thus I'll be, endlessly falling,
誰にも見つけられないのかな
won't anyone find me?
どこへ向かい、何をすれば？
Where am I headed, what am I to do?
ふと射し込む一筋の光
Suddenly, a beam of light shone through.
手を伸ばれば届きそうだけど
I stuck out my hand, and seemed to reach,
波に拐われて見失った
but it was carried out of sight by the waves.
あれは一体なんだったのだろうな
Just what was that, I wondered?
あたたかくて眩しかったの
So warm and dazzling...
無意識のカウンターイルミネーション
An unconscious counter-illumination...
嘘つきは誰?
and who's the liar?
深海少女 まだまだ沈む
The deep-sea girl, sinking ever still,
暗闇の彼方へ閉じこめる
shut away beyond the darkness.
深海少女 だけど知りたい
The deep-sea girl, yet still she wants to know,
心惹かれるあの人を見つけたから
for she's found the one who captivates her heart...
昼も夜も無かったこの場所に
Even in this place with no noons or nights,
なのに眠れない夜は続く
sleepless nights continue on.
自由の羽大きく広げて
With your free wings spread wide,
泳ぐあなたは綺麗でした
you were beautiful as you swam.
そしてまた光は降りそそぐ
And then once more light poured down,
見とれていたら目が合った
and dazzled, we met eyes.
気付いてこっちを振り返るあなたに
You who noticed and looked back toward me,
嘘つきな私…
and I, the liar...
深海少女 わざわざ沈む
The deep-sea girl, sinking willfully,
暗闇のさなかに赤い頬
red-cheeked in the midst of darkness.
深海少女 裸心の心を見せる勇気
The deep-sea girl, who would bare her heart...
黒い海がまだ許さない
The black sea would still not allow her the courage.
こんなに服は汚れてしまって
My clothes have been dirtied so,
笑顔も醜くゆがんでいった
my smile been shamefully warped.
誰にも合わせる顔なんてないの もう放っておいてよ!
Do I look like I want to get along with anyone? Just leave me alone!
声にならない気持ちが溢れてとけた
I overflowed with feelings I couldn't voice,
次の瞬間、君が突然姿を消した
and in the next moment, you suddenly vanished.
心配性の彼女は焦る 闇が彼を隠しひとりきり
The uneasy girl hurried; the darkness hid him, kept him alone.
限界少女 その手を伸ばす
The unfree girl, she puts out her hand:
「ほらね、君も素敵な色を隠してた」
"See, you've been hiding brilliant colors, too..."
深海少女 腕を引かれる
The deep-sea girl, pulling by the arm,
歌う祝福のマリンスノー
sings a blessing of marine snow.
深海少女 もっと知りたい
The deep-sea girl, she wants to know more,
心惹かれるあの人を見つけたから
for she's found the one who captivates her heart...
深海少女 筆を光らせる
The deep-sea girl, her brush aglow,
歌う祝福のマリスの
singing a blessing of malice...
深海少女 もっと知りたい
The deep-sea girl, she wants to know more,
心惹かれるあの人を見つけたから…
for she's found the one who captivates her heart...
この海を出て 今飛び立つんだ
Leave this sea, and now, fly away...
常識 感性 倫理観 持って持って
Have common sense, sensitivity, and ethics!
経済的余裕も持って持って
Have financial leeway as well!
あげた指輪もあげた
The ring I gave you, I gave you...
喧嘩をしたらとまったね
When we fought, you stopped right there.
間の声がなのもうわがままでしょ
Love and romance and all that must be a misunderstanding.
でも今度更新するとかめちゃいいでしょ
But updating this time would be amazing, right?
震える心うずいてるからさ
My trembling heart is aching so,
裏腹食わばら手を取り合うのがさだめ
contradictory and fearful, holding hands is our destiny.
結婚しましょうそうしましょう死ぬまであなたと一緒
Let's get married, let's do that—together with you until I die.
結婚しましょうそうしましょうあなたの顔しか拝めない
Let's get married, let's do that—I can only gaze at your face.
ああ辞める時も健やかな時も手を取り合うのがさだめ
Ah, whether in sickness or in health, holding hands is our destiny.
結婚しましょうそうしましょうようやくひとつになれるかな
Let's get married, let's do that—can we finally become one?
いつかあなた香り変わって下世話な男になって
Someday your scent will change, becoming a vulgar man,
触れる肌も背中合わせ憧れが腐って
our touching skin back-to-back, our admiration rotting away.
本当に大事なものあげた人でも期待が普通にのまれてね
Even for someone I gave precious things to, expectations are simply swallowed up.
心臓ばっかならべてよなちょうでしょ
Lining up only hearts in the dead of night, right?
どうせ裏切り合うのが見えるでしょう
After all, you can see us betraying each other.
壊れる未来があるならばお伽話なんが
If there is a future that breaks, then fairy tales...
結婚しましょうそうしましょう死ぬまであなたと一緒
Let's get married, let's do that—together with you until I die.
結婚しましょうそうしましょうあなたの顔しか拝めない
Let's get married, let's do that—I can only gaze at your face.
ああ辞める時も健やかな時も手を取り合うのがさだめ
Ah, whether in sickness or in health, holding hands is our destiny.
結婚しましょうそうしましょうようやくひとつになれるかな
Let's get married, let's do that—can we finally become one?
結婚しましょうそうしましょう
Let's get married, let's do that.
結婚しましょうそうしましょう死ぬまであなたと一緒
Let's get married, let's do that—together with you until I die.
結婚しましょうそうしましょうあなたの顔しか拝めない
Let's get married, let's do that—I can only gaze at your face.
ああ辞める時も健やかな時も手を取り合うのがさだめ
Ah, whether in sickness or in health, holding hands is our destiny.
結婚しましょうそうしましょうようやくひとつになれるかな
Let's get married, let's do that—can we finally become one?
ねぇ ニア 誰かを笑い飛ばさなきゃ
Hey Nia, if we don't laugh someone away,
自分を許せないような くだらない人間のこと
those foolish people who can't forgive themselves—
キミはどう思う？
what do you think of them?
ねぇ ニア 他人の歩幅を眺めて
Hey Nia, watching other people's strides
意味もなく駆け足になる つまらない人間のこと
and pointlessly rushing ahead, those boring people—
キミはどう思う？
what do you think of them?
ねぇ ニア 笑顔で過ごす日々を
Hey Nia, spending days smiling
当たり前と思うような 傲慢な人間のこと
and taking it for granted, those arrogant people—
キミはどう思う？
what do you think of them?
カタチのないフタシカナモノはいつでもケイサンをクルワセてしまうの
Things without shape and certainty always throw calculations out of whack,
だけれど
but...
ああ 僕はまだ信じてる ココロのないキミに問いかけたのは
Ah, I still believe. Why did I pose this question to you, who have no heart?
キミの手が僕よりもあたたかかったからさ
Because your hand was warmer than mine.
ねぇ ニア 子供の頃に見てた
Hey Nia, that dream we saw in childhood
あの夢の続きがこんな未来に繋がってたこと
connecting to a future like this—
キミはどう思う？
what do you think?
ゆれる街灯 穿つ雨
Swaying street lights, pelting rain
揺れる感情 感覚のテレパス
Trembling emotions, telepath of senses
迷子のふたりはコンタクト ココロは恋を知りました
Two lost children make contact, my heart learned of love
タイトロープ ツギハギの制服
Tightrope, stitched uniform
重度のディスコミュニケーション
Severe discommunication
眼光赤色にキラキラ
Eyes sparkling red
ナニカが起きる胸騒ぎ
Anxiety that something will happen
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, I'm an alien
あなたの心を惑わす
Confuse your mind
交ざりあう宇宙の引力で
With the intertwined gravity of the universe
感じている気持ちはトキメキ
The feeling I'm feeling is excitement
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, your alien
引きあう心は逃れられない
I can't escape the pulling hearts
あなたに未体験あげる
I'll give you a new experience
異世界の見果てまで トキメキ スキ
To the end of another world, excitement, I love you
Hello, hello, I'm an alien, I love you
点灯と消灯を
Fluorescent lights that repeatedly
繰り返している蛍光灯
turn on and off
超常な混沌が
Supernatural chaos
静かにあなたを蝕んだ
quietly eroded you
並行な信号は
Parallel signals
特異点に因み交わった
intersected due to a singularity
創造現実盲信症候群
Creation reality blind faith syndrome
感応性本能
Sensitive instinct
シンドローム ひとりきり夜な夜な
Syndrome, all alone night after night
空想 描くまるであのグリモワ
Imagining, drawing like a grimoire
サーチライト 避ける遊走機
Searchlight avoiding floating machine
「まだあなたはすべてを知りたい?」
"Do you still want to know everything?"
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, I'm an alien
あなたの心を惑わす
Confuse your mind
瞳に映らない引力に
Notice the gravity that doesn't reflect
気づいてよ わたしは
in my eyes, I am
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, your alien
触れあえば 傷は二度と消えない
If we touch, wounds will never disappear
降りそそぐ 無数の隕石も
Countless meteorites raining down
とめどない心は届かない!
Can't reach your fluttering heart!
エイリアン ふたりはエイリアン
Alien, we are aliens
高鳴る 気持ちは 抑えられない!
Can't control the pounding feeling!
あなた は未確認生命体
You are an unidentified life form
異世界の見果てまで あなたが好き
To the end of another world, I love you
Hello, hello, I'm an alien, I love you
垂れ流した テレビの音
Droopy TV sound
溜めてしまった 洗濯物は今日こそ
Piled up laundry, today of all days
晴れでもあえて 外には出ないでいよう
Let's dare not go out even in sunny weather
映らないスナックと アルコールで乾杯をしよう
Let's toast with un-photogenic snacks and alcohol
2人酸いも甘いも 噛み合わないとしても
Even if two people, through thick and thin, don't mesh
お互い寄り添うように 少しずらしてみようよ
Let's lean on each other, let's shift a little bit
君がくれた太陽 月で隠れないように
The sun you gave me, so the moon doesn't hide it
輝き弥まぬように歌うメロディ
Singing the melody so its brilliance never slackens
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Going past "I love you"
似た者同士こうして
Like this, as kindred spirits
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to laugh together until we grow old
君がいないと Lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed.
Falling asleep in bed in my dreams
起こすから Morning callで
I'll wake you up with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
脱ぎっ放しの足跡辿る
Following the footprints left behind
不意をついて後ろから抱きつくの
Catching you off guard and hugging you from behind
つい、繰り返すと忘れてしまいそうになるよ
If I repeat it too much, I might almost forget
振り返ると日々に当たり前じゃないこと
Looking back, realizing that every day isn't taken for granted
2人対の細胞 絡み合う特別を
A pair of cells intertwine, wanting to live
噛み締めて生きたいと思った まどろみ抱く正午
Savoring the specialness, embracing slumber at noon
吐息、漏れた体温 微塵も逃さないように
Breath, leaked body heat, not missing a single particle
頭の中刻む甘いメモリー
Sweet memories carved into my mind
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Going past "I love you"
違う者同士こうして
Like this, as different people
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to laugh together until we grow old
君がいないと Lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed.
Falling asleep in bed in my dreams
起こすから Morning callで
I'll wake you up with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手はね離さないでいて
Please don't let go of our overlapping hands
ごめん、これぞそばに居たいだけだね
Sorry, I just want to stay by your side
抱えた想いは お互い様でしょ
The feelings we carry are mutual, right?
ほら、おあいこでしょ
Look, we're even, aren't we?
すれ違い、間違いもあるし 筋書き通り行かない
There are misunderstandings and mistakes, things don't go according to script
打診、悲しみだって 半分こにしよう
Let's share probing thoughts and sadness in half
別れじゃない 希望 独りよがりにならないように、いつも
Hope, not goodbye, so as not to be self-righteous, always
君がいないと ロンリー ロンリーで
Without you, lonely lonely
夢の中 フォレスト イン ベッド
Falling asleep in bed in my dreams
ここからもう一度コールで
From here once more with a call
I protect you from line my baby
違うもの同士こうして
Like this, as different people
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to laugh together until we grow old
君がいないと ロンリー ロンリーで
Without you, lonely lonely
夢の中 フォレスト イン ベッド
Falling asleep in bed in my dreams
ここからもう一度コールで
From here once more with a call
I protect you from line my baby
重ねた手はね...
Overlapping hands...
垂れ流した テレビの音
The droning television sound
泥めいてしまった 洗濯物は今日こそ
The laundry that's gotten murky, today of all days
晴れでもあえて外には出ないでおこうね
Let's dare not go outside even if it's clear
映えないスナックとアルコールで乾杯をしよう
Let's toast with unglamorous snacks and alcohol
2人酸いも甘いも噛み合わないとしても
Even if the two of us don't quite mesh through sweet and sour
お互い寄り添うように少しずらしてみようよ
Let's try shifting a bit so we lean on each other
君がくれた太陽 月で隠れないように
So the sun you gave me isn't hidden by the moon
輝き攣まないように歌うメロディ
Singing a melody so its brilliance never fades
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Dallying through a slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Going beyond even "I love you"
似た者同士こうして年老いるまで笑っていたいね
Like kindred spirits, I want us to laugh until we grow old
君がいないと lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed.
Falling asleep in bed inside a dream
起こすから morning callで I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
I'll wake you up with a morning call and protect you from nightmares
脱ぎっ放しの足跡辿ると
Tracing the trail of discarded footprints
不意をついて後ろから抱きつくの
Catching you off guard and hugging you from behind
繰り返すと忘れてしまそうになるよ
Repeating it, I almost forget
振り返えると日々が当たり前じゃないこと
Looking back, realizing these days aren't just guaranteed
2人対の細胞絡み合う特別を噛み締めて生きたいと思った
Intertwining like a pair of cells, I want to live savoring that special bond
まどろみ抱く正午 吐息 漏れた体温 微塵も逃さないように
Embracing slumber at noon, so not a single breath escapes
頭の中刻む甘いメモリー
Sweet memories carved into my mind
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Dallying through a slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Going beyond even "I love you"
違う者同士こうして年老いるまで笑っていたいね
Unlike spirits, I want us to laugh until we grow old
君がいないと lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed.
Falling asleep in bed inside a dream
起こすから morning callで I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
I'll wake you up with a morning call and protect you from nightmares
重ねた手はね離さないでいて
Please don't let go of our overlapped hands
ごめんね、これ
Sorry, this...
そばに居たいだけなんだ
I just want to stay by your side
抱えた想いは お互い様でしょ
The feelings we carry are mutual, right?
ほら、相合子でしょ
Look, we share an umbrella, don't we?
すれ違い、間違いもあるし 筋書き通り行かない
There are misunderstandings, mistakes, and things don't go to script
打診、悲しみだって半分こにしよう
Let's split even our inquiries and sorrows in half
別れじゃない希望 独りよがりにならないように
A hope that isn't a parting, so we aren't selfish
いつも
Always...
はーいというわけで今回は深海少女とずっと一緒に踊った
So, this time, I danced the whole time with Deep Sea Girl
二管生紺色、そしてみよW/X/Yでしたー！
Nikansen Kon'iro, and look, it was W/X/Y!
初出しの曲も何個かあって、いかがでしたか？ えー、最初のやつ可愛かったでしょ？
There were several songs shown for the first time, how was it? The first one was cute, right?
そう、いーっぱい曲のあったんだけど、うーん、これってなったやつはこちらでございました。
Yeah, there were lots of songs, but the one that made me go "this one!" was right here.
これにはまたね、裏話があると思いますので、またお喋りしたいなと思います。ね、みんなのイラストもね振ってまいりました。可愛かったでしょ？
There's probably a behind-the-scenes story to this, so I'd love to chat again. Everyone's illustrations fluttered in too!
そして、ぼくのパッチんで深海に降りてきたんだけど、いやぼくにはい？
And, I came down to the deep sea with my snap, but wait, do I?
ぼくパッチンの才能あったかもしれない 音は聞こえなかったんだけどさ、うーん、生きるらしい。
Maybe I had a talent for snapping? I couldn't hear any sound though, apparently I live.
そしてブランシュドール衣装でございます！ 実はこの衣装、ライブの3Dでできるのは初めて！ 表情もちゃんと変わります。可愛いでしょう？
And here is the Blanche d'Or outfit! Doing this outfit in 3D for a live is a first! My facial expressions change properly too. Cute, right?
ね？可愛いでしょう？今回はこちらの衣装をもとにアトロポリスは作られております。
Right? Cute, right? Atropolis was created based on this outfit this time.
可愛い、可愛い、ふぅふぅ、あ！これ！あ、待って！
Cute, cute, phew phew, ah! This! Ah, wait!
これK-POPの、あ、このカメラ！あ、やばい。待って、ちょでK-POPのアイドルで見たことがあるカメラだ。
This is a K-POP, ah, this camera! Ah, oh no. Wait, it's a camera I've seen in K-POP idols before.
カメラの場所探せこれ！え、待って！今で見つけらんなかった。ここ！ここ！ここ！ここ！
Find the camera's location! Uh, wait! I couldn't find it just now. Here! Here! Here! Here!
あ、う、どこ？やばい！やばい！え、どここれ？手上げたら余計わかんないんだけど、ここ！ここ！え？ここ！うわ、違う！
Ah, u, where? Oh no! Where is this? Raising my hand makes it even more confusing, but here! Here! Huh? Here! Whoa, wrong!
ここ！ここ！え、やってる？ここ！え、ここじゃない？違うななんか。あれれれれれれ、え？
Here! Here! Uh, are you doing it? Here! Huh, isn't it here? Something's wrong. Huhhhh, huh?
次！えー！ここ！わかるんだよね。
Next! Eh! Here! You know, I get it.
ここーーーーっ！あはははははは！
Hereーーーー! Ahahahaha!
というか、やばい。びっくりした、なんか気恥ずかしさを感じた。結構カメラ難しいかもしれない。
I mean, oh no. I was surprised, felt a bit bashful. Cameras might be quite difficult.
楽しかった。というわけで、なんとここで重大告知があります！それはこちらの動画をご覧ください。どうぞ。
It was fun. And with that, there is an important announcement right here! Please take a look at this video. Here you go.
ロボ子さん 1st Album 発売決定
[Title: Roboco's 1st Album Release Confirmed]
ロボ子さんのみんな、お待たせー！
Everyone, thanks for waiting!
ついに、ロボ子のファーストアルバム『Jewel Memory』の発売が決定したよー！
At long last, the release of Roboco's 1st album, "Jewel Memory," has been decided!
これまでロボ子と一緒に過ごしてきた時間や思い出のひとつひとつが、ロボ子にとっては宝物の宝石なんだ。
Every single moment and memory spent together with Roboco is a precious gem to me.
だから、その宝石を収めた宝箱のようなアルバムになってほしいなっていう想いを込めたよ。
That's why I put my heart into making it an album like a treasure chest holding those gems.
全16曲の順番や構成にもこだわっているから、楽しみにしていてね。
I've paid special attention to the order and arrangement of all 16 tracks, so please look forward to it.
なんと、新曲も収録されるよ！
What's more, new songs are also included!
さらに、同梱物にはアルバム本体を飾って保管できるアクリルケースがついてくるんだ！
Furthermore, bundled items include an acrylic case to display and store the album itself!
ロボ子の他のグッズと一緒に、お部屋に飾ってね。
Please display it in your room along with Roboco's other goods.
他にも、みんなが喜んでくれるような同梱物を用意しているよ。
I've also prepared other bundled goods that everyone will love.
詳細は予約ページを見てね。
Please check the reservation page for details.
CD予約の開始はこの後21時から、ロボ子はちゃんとするんだよ！
CD reservations start at 21:00 tonight, so Roboco will definitely be checking!
はーい、ということでなんとアルバムが出まーす！詳しくはおもんばいサイト等をご確認してみてください。
Hi! So, amazingly, the album is coming out! Please check the official website for details.
えー、お待たせしました！
Umm, sorry to keep you waiting!
やっとアルバム出せた！嬉しい！
We finally got an album out! I'm so happy!
え、めちゃめちゃかっこよくなかったですか？ビジュ。
Um, wasn't it super cool? The visuals.
一体何が入っているのか全部で10曲あるんですけれども、
What on earth is inside? There are 10 songs in total, but...
3曲なんと新しい新曲がありますよ！楽しみにしててね。
3 of them are brand new songs! Please look forward to them.
そしてこの後はなんとそのアルバムの中から1曲の新曲披露したいなと思います。
And after this, I'd like to premiere a brand new song from that album.
さらにこの配信の後MVもMVも、むにゃむにゃになっちゃった。MVもプレミアム公開されるのでぜひみんなチェックしてってください！
Furthermore, after this stream, the MV will also—mumble mumble—the MV will be premiered, so please check it out!
あ、ちなみに僕の歌声にメロメロになった方は今すぐメンバーに入って、このあと人間の配信もあるし、1曲歌いますよ！
Oh, by the way, for those who fell head over heels for my singing voice, join the membership right now, there's human streaming after this too, and I'll sing a song!
もうちょっとね、ロボ子さんと楽しみたいと思います。まだこれで終わりじゃないんだから。
I want to enjoy a bit more with Roboco-san. It's not ending with just this, you know.
この配信が終わってもプレミアム動画もあるしメンバー限定配信もあるので、ぜひ両方とも楽しみにしててください！
Even after this stream ends, there's a premium video and member-exclusive stream, so please look forward to both!
新曲はみんな漢字の名前を間違えないようにしてね。
For the new song, everyone make sure you don't get the kanji name wrong.
『現世アリス』
"Utsusemi Alice"
ちょっとメロいかも？
Maybe a bit mellow?
それでは最後の曲聞いていってください。『現世アリス』
Well then, please listen to the final song. "Utsusemi Alice"
不思議の国や御伽話でも
Even in Wonderland or fairy tales,
見れない現世までご招待
I invite you to a reality you've never seen.
異国にに取り残されたみたいだ
It feels like being left behind in a foreign land,
知らない言葉に戸惑う
Bewildered by unfamiliar words.
誰もが心を嘘で隠して
Everyone hides their heart with lies,
運命を作ろう、どれが正解？
Creating fate, which one is correct?
今くらいはさらけ出してみてよ
For now, try revealing yourself.
忘れられないような光景を君に届けるから
Because I'll deliver a scenery you'll never forget straight to you.
その目に焼き付けてみてね
Burn it into your eyes, won't you?
画面越しの悲しいニュースに酔って
Intoxicated by the sad news through the screen,
仲間の些細なミスに怒って、囚われて流されて
Angered by a comrade's trivial mistakes, captured and swept away,
日々に嫌気さしても
Even if you grow sick of daily life,
忘れられないような光景を君に届けるから
Because I'll deliver a scenery you'll never forget to you,
その目に焼き付けてみてね
Burn it into your eyes, won't you?
忘れさせるなんて大そうなことは言えないけど
I can't say anything as grand as making you forget,
ちょっとでも寄り添えるように夜明けまで連れ出すよ
But so I can stay close, even just a little, I'll take you out until dawn.
コンクリートの森をさまよえば
When wandering through the concrete forest,
見慣れた街だって迷路
even a familiar town becomes a maze.
誰もが自分を役で演じて
Everyone plays a role as themselves,
笑顔が貼り付いた これが正体
with a glued-on smile—this is our true form.
無理に笑わなくていい
You don't have to force a smile,
仮面なんて剥がして 魔法に
peel off the mask and let the magic
映る君を抱いて
embrace the reflection of you.
流行り物の空気にダンス踊って
Dancing to the atmosphere of trends,
また右倣え人の声に倣って
following the crowd once more, mimicking others' voices,
歌があって躓いて 遊びを消しても
even if songs exist, you stumble, erasing playfulness,
消えないような感情を 君と分け合うから
because I will share these indelible feelings with you.
その声を聴かせて見せて ねぇ
Let me hear and see that voice, hey...
救い出すだなんて傲慢なことは言えないけど
I can't say something as arrogant as "saving you," but
ちょっとでも軽くなるように
so that your burden feels a little lighter,
その手を引くよ アリス
I will take your hand, Alice.
みんなからもいつもパワーもらってるよ♪
I always get power from everyone too ♪
たくさんのキモチをこめて ありがとう♡
Thank you with all my heart ♡
これからもそばにいてね
Please stay by my side from now on too
ロボ子さん生誕ライブ2026
[Roboco Birthday Live 2026]